Finding Aid for the Diane Williams Collection of Papers and Photographs, 1966-1991
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Diane Williams Collection of Papers and Photographs, 1966-1991
Mus. Arc. 84
Williams, Diane, 1940-
1 box (16 folders, 34 photographs)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection contains a small amount of correspondence, concert programs and advertisements, clippings, and photographs.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Diane Williams, 2017.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Diane Wiens Williams was born 22 November 1940 in Kansas City, Missouri. She earned her Bachelor's Degree in Music from Oberlin, with studies in viola with William Berman and in voice with Robert Fountain. She continued her studies at the Manhattan School of Music where she studied viola with William Lincer and Lillian Fuchs. Later, she earned a Master's Degree in School Counseling at the University at Buffalo.
Diane Williams moved to Buffalo with her husband, percussionist Jan Williams, in 1964. The couple met while attending the Manhattan School of Music and married in 1962. She was hired as a member of the viola section in the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra in 1964 and remained in the position until 1996. Williams has also performed at the Ojai Music Festival in California, the Cayuga Chamber Orchestra, the Western New York Chamber Orchestra, the Erie Philharmonic, the SONOR ensemble at the University of California at San Diego. She often performed with various chamber ensembles in Buffalo, including the Custer and Taub string quartets, and the Camenae String Quartet of which she was a founding member.
Diane Williams is a member and officer of the Wednesday Morning Musicale, an organization of women musicians in Western New York founded in 1925. She has served as a New York State certified Ombudsman at a Buffalo inner city nursing home and is a professional music engraver.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains a small amount of correspondence, concert programs and advertisements, clippings, and photographs.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
I. Papers
II. Photographs
Container List
- Papers, 1966-1991, I.; Folder 1-16
  Contains correspondence, programs, and clippings.
  - Correspondence, 1974-1991, 5 pieces (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Camenae String Quartet business cards, undated, 2 cards (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1972-1975, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1977-1979, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1980-1981, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Programs, 1982-1983, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Programs, 1984-1985, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Programs, 1988-1990, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1966, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1974-1977, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1978-1979, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1980, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1981, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1982-1983, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1984-1985, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Programs and clippings, undated, 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Photographs, 1967-1985, I.; Item 17-40
  Contains 34 photographs and several strips of negatives.
  Chiefly arranged in chronological order.
  - Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra at Kleinhans Hall, with conductor Michael Tilson Thomas, 1971, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified photographer (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Camenae String Quartet on stage: Diane Williams, viola, Marie Yadzinski and Sue Harbison, violin, Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, circa 1976, 1 black and white photographic proof sheet; Photograph by Jay Wells (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Camenae String Quartet proof sheet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photographic proof sheet; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Camenae String Quartet proof sheet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photographic proof sheet; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Camenae String Quartet proof sheet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photographic proof sheet; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 39)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Sheryl Krohn and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1981, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Don Harry (Box 1, Item 41)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Diana Aylward and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1983, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Ansgarius Aylward (Box 1, Item 42)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Diana Aylward and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1983, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Ansgarius Aylward (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Diana Aylward and Donald McCrorey, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1983, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified photographer (Box 1, Item 44)
  - Nils Vigeland at performance by the Camenae String Quartet at the Burchfield Center, 21 April 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified photographer (Box 1, Item 45)
  - Nils Vigeland at performance by the Camenae String Quartet at the Burchfield Center, with Diane Williams, Mary Sue Wells, and Igor Prince, 21 April 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified photographer (Box 1, Item 46)
  - Nils Vigeland at performance by the Camenae String Quartet at the Burchfield Center, with Diane Williams, Mary Sue Wells, and Igor Prince, 21 April 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified photographer (Box 1, Item 47)
  - Jan Williams conducting at performance by the Camenae String Quartet at the Burchfield Center, with Bruce Penner, percussion, Edward Yadzinski, clarinet, and Mary Sue Wells, violoncello, 21 April 1980, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified photographer (Box 1, Item 48)
  - Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Diana Aylward and Robert Prokes, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, circa 1984, 1 black and white photograph; Photograph by Ansgarius Aylward (Box 1, Item 49)
  - Conductor Joseph Wincenc with the Camenae String Quartet: Diane Williams, viola, Melanie Gugala Haas and Robert Prokes, violin, Robert Hausmann, violoncello, 17 February 1985, 1 black and white photograph; Unidentified photographer (Box 1, Item 50)
    Signed by Wincenc in appreciation of performance with the Amherst Symphony.
  - Negative strips, undated, 3 pockets of strips; Unidentified photographer (Box 1, Folder 51-53)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Williams, Diane, 1940-; Camenae String Quartet; Women musicians--New York (State)--Buffalo; Women violists--New York (State)--Buffalo; String quartets (Musical groups)--New York (State)--Buffalo
Genres
Correspondence; Concert programs; Clippings (information artifacts); Photographs